

At Alten Sweden we develop and deliver expertise for world-leading companies and have a committed team of engineers and IT consultants. Our customers are found in the Energy, Telecom, Automotive, Defence & Aerospace and other industries and we cover the whole product development cycle. We are a part of the Alten Group and have a workforce of over 20.000 in 23 countries.

Page 1 (2)

### Aditya Amrutha Nalluri | CV

Veckovägen 65, LGH 1302 177 62 JÄRFÄLLA Stockholm, Sweden Ph No: +46 725 46 4768

Email ID: adityaamruthanalluri@gmail.com

Latest updated: 2016-02-13

### **SUMMARY**



I am qualified as a software engineer specializing in computer science & Engineering. I enjoy working as Software Engineer and can write in the following languages (C, OOP's in C++ & Basic JAVA).

With 3 years of working as a software engineer in Defence Domain, I became more involved in the software testing side so looking at software modules which had been written and testing it before people got to use it in real life and ensure that it did not have any bugs and make sure that we deliver the high quality software to the customer.

Most likely my work experience includes following activities:

- Working on different types of Black Box testing viz. Functional,
   Integration, System, Smoke, Compatibility, Accessibility, Regression,
   Unit test, performance testing and Database testing.
- Responsibilities includes the planning, developing, implementing and Documenting tests.
- Working knowledge about Version Control System like Clear case, GIT, GERRIT, GitHub, Eclipse & Android Studio.
- Good knowledge on Test Automation Tool QTP/UFT.
- Trouble shooting and debugging of SW modules.
- Design new test cases based on Change Requests and updating of existing
  - Test cases when requirements change.
- Writing Test case in an agile environment utilizing Test Driven Development (TDD) approach.
- Review and give input on Requirement documentation from a test Perspective

Additional Training on :

Protocols: TCP/IP, UDP, DNS, FTP, SNMP, SMTP, SIP, HTTPS, IPsec, SSL Security Algorithms: AES, DES, RSA, SHA, MD5, RC4, Firewalls

I am a technical person by nature but I also pay great attention to detail in my work and like to be very hands on in my role and get a sense of enjoyment out of ensuring that the products that are unleashed on the public have been written and tested correctly.

### COMPETENCE OVERVIEW

Specialist area

Operating systems Languages and techniques Tools 2 years of project experience in SW testing and 6 months of project experience in C++ programming as a SW Developer in Defence Domain. Windows, Embedded Linux

C, C++, Manual Testing, VB scripting SQL + DB-Design, HTML, Java Script, Perl.

QTP/ UTF, Regression Testing, Unit tests, White-Box Testing, Black-Box, Eclipse, GitHub, and Gerrit.



At Alten Sweden we develop and deliver expertise for world-leading companies and have a committed team of engineers and IT consultants. Our customers are found in the Energy, Telecom, Automotive, Defence & Aerospace and other industries and we cover the whole product development cycle. We are a part of the Alten Group and have a workforce of over 20.000 in 23 countries.

Page 2 (2)

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Dec 2015 - Feb 2016

## Application Tester (Short Assignment), Westindia Technology AB, Sweden

- Testing Mobile Application like Zinznio Balance & Golfin Mobile Apps.
- Troubleshooting and solving customer trouble reports.
- Prepare and execute of test cases as per requirement.

#### 2012 - 2013

## Associate Test Engineer (SW Tester), HCL Info Sys Pvt Ltd. Bangalore, INDIA

- Developed Client-Server architecture capable of transferring fragmented
  - Messages over TCP and UDP sockets in networking environment.
- Prepare and execute of test cases as per requirement.
- Writing Test case in an agile environment utilizing Test Driven Development (TDD) approach
- Involved in preparing the traceability matrix.
- Preparing Defect Report and assigning the defects to developer.
- Involved in system and Functional testing.
- Mapping functional requirements with test cases.

### 2013 - 2014

### SW Developer (C++), HCL Info Sys Pvt Ltd. Bangalore, INDIA

Due to a rapid enhancement in the electronic commerce technology, the use of credit card has dramatically increased. As credit card becomes the most popular mode of payment for both online as well as regular purchases, cases associated with it are also increasing. In this model the sequence of operations in credit card transaction processing using Hidden Markov Model for detecting frauds. An HMM is initially trained with the normal behavior of a cardholder.

### **EDUCATION, TRAINING & QUALIFICATIONS**

#### 2008 - 2012

# Basic & further education (4 Year's Degree), JNTU, Kakinada, INDIA Bachelor of Technology Computer Science & Engineering. 240p Courses:

• Computer programming and Data Structures, Electronic Devices and ckts, Digital logic Design, Advanced Data Structures, Unix & Shell Programming, OOP concept, Software Testing Methodologies, Database management systems, Software Engineering, Information security, Network Programming, TCP, UDP, SSL, SMTP, SNMP, networking protocols, Client-Server Model, Micro-processors & Interfacing.

### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Personal qualities Reading Books, Indore games, music. Sudoku solving. Creative thinking and

initiative. Friendly in nature and helping to other.

Interests and hobbies Driving, travelling and meet new people.

Driver's license NO
Nationality Indian
Language English
Other Married
Year of birth 1990-09-15